<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lennart Damen – </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Lennart Damen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 20:45:07 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On Dutch immigration policy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/on_dutch_immigration_policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 21:01:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/on_dutch_immigration_policy/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;If you know me, you know that I generally refrain from having opinions on topics that I do not know much about. However, with the recent shift of power in the Dutch government towards right-wing populist (and &lt;a href=&#34;https://watwilwilders.nl/WildersdiscrimineertMoslims.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;openly racist&lt;/a&gt;) parties, I feel that some of the values I care about are under pressure. I talked about this topic with some colleagues (during Christmas dinner, after a few glasses of wine), and wanted to share some of my concerns with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find it difficult to articulate my general feeling of uneasiness. Instead, I chose two to highlight two developments that worry me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tweedekamer.nl/kamerstukken/moties/detail?id=2024Z19345&amp;amp;did=2024D46011&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The motion Becker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ind.nl/nl/nieuws/voorlopig-geen-beslissing-op-asielaanvragen-syrie&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The freeze of asylum requests from Syrian refugees one single day after the fall of Assad&amp;rsquo;s regime&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The motion Becker&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The motion (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.parlement.com/id/vh8lnhrogvv2/motie&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;defition&lt;/a&gt;) Becker requests the government &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip; to collect data about cultural/religious values of Dutch citizens with a migration background, for example by asking {institution} to (periodically) carry out this investigation&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have several issues with the framing of this motion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is unconstitutional, because it does not treat all those that reside in the Netherlands as equal. While I do agree that collecting census data may help to improve the integration process, I do not think any laws should be framed around targeting specific parts of the population. This sends a message of division to both native and immigrated inhabitants of the Netherlands.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is ambiguous*, and therefore susceptible to abuse of power by either current or future governments. Even though I believe Becker&amp;rsquo;s idea may be well intended (which I do believe watching &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/bentebecker/status/1864705413624496294&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;her reaction to the backlash&lt;/a&gt;), allowing these kinds of laws&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only after the motion passed parliament, it gained a decent amount of negative attention &lt;a href=&#34;https://nos.nl/artikel/2547828-berouw-extra-uitleg-en-vingerwijzen-in-kamer-na-opschudding-over-vvd-migrantenonderzoek&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;in the media&lt;/a&gt;. In response, some parties withdrew their support for the motion (perhaps more out of fear for losing their voters than out of genuine understanding and regret).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* The motion does not mention any restrictions towards what kind of data should be collected, that privacy will be protected, or who &amp;ldquo;people with a migration background&amp;rdquo; are. I understand that a motion should not go too much into detail, but still, I would expect some mention of limitations towards the collection process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The freeze of asylum requests from Syrian refugees&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;on December 9th 2024, &amp;hellip;.I still need to finish this.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
